<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>praj-mkdir</title>
    <link>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on praj-mkdir</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.146.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://praj-mkdir.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handling File Upload Status with S3 Pre-Signed URLs</title>
      <link>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/posts/s3_upload_status/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/posts/s3_upload_status/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While working on a project, I decided to use S3 pre-signed URLs for file uploads. The main reason was that I didn’t want my backend server to handle large files directly. If a 500MB file came in, routing it through the server would increase latency, consume bandwidth, and unnecessarily load the application. With pre-signed URLs, the backend just generates a temporary signed URL, gives it to the client, and the client uploads directly to S3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Apache Kafka with Spring Boot</title>
      <link>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/posts/kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/posts/kafka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;integrating-apache-kafka-with-spring-boot&#34;&gt;Integrating Apache Kafka with Spring Boot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Kafka is a robust distributed event-streaming platform that enables high-throughput, real-time data pipelines and event-driven applications. Integrating Kafka with Spring Boot provides developers with a seamless way to produce and consume messages, making it ideal for building scalable and resilient systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will guide you through setting up Kafka integration with Spring Boot using Spring Kafka&amp;rsquo;s auto-configuration. By the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a functional Spring Boot application with a producer, consumer, and controller to test the setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/blogs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there! I’m Prajwal, a Software Engineer with a strong interest in building reliable backend systems and working with cloud and security technologies. I did my Bachelor’s in Electronics and Communication from KLS Gogte Institute of Technology, and over time I’ve found myself drawn to solving problems around how applications scale, stay secure, and perform under real-world conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my work and learning revolves around backend development, cloud infrastructure, and security things like designing APIs, securing applications, and exploring ways to make systems production-ready. I enjoy the mix of engineering and problem-solving that comes with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact me</title>
      <link>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://praj-mkdir.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Best way to get in touch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/prajwalspatil/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:praj2patil9@gmail.com&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/praj-mkdir/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
